WILLIAM SEBAN

Oceanside, CA 92057 310.408.6461

https://www.linkedin.com/in/williamseban https://github.com/wseban?tab=repositories William.c.seban@gmail.com

Project Manager/Full Stack Software Developer

Full stack web developer, accomplished project manager and prior Army Captain with a, previously held, top-secret security clearance and 12 years of leadership experience. Respected leader, organizer, and manager, able to plan and implement programs for short and long-term objectives. Experienced in project management, web-APIs (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), third-party APIs (jQuery, Bootstrap, google fonts), server-side APIs, and building RESTful API and GraphQL queries and mutations. Areas of expertise include:

HTML5, CSS and JavaScript jQuery and Bootstrap Agile workflow

Writing Node.js Utilizing NoSQL Database React.js Object Oriented Programming
MERN Development
Communication

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND

Full Stack Coding Bootcamp Certificate - UC Berkeley; December 2022

Lean Six Sigma, Yellow Belt - Fayetteville Technical Community College; March 2017 Entry Level Leadership and Management Training - Army Logistics University; November 2013 Bachelor of Science, Criminal Justice - San Diego State University; May 2013

PROJECTS

Cookie Corner

https://cmcookiecorner.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/wseban/Cookie-Corner

- Fully functioning and reactive cookie purchasing website.
- Skills: HTML5, React.js, React-Icons, React-Router, React-Bootstrap, Javascript, Emailjs, MongoDB, MongooseODM, Sweetalert.js

Weather Dashboard

https://wseban.github.io/Weather-Dashboard/ | https://github.com/wseban/Weather-Dashboard

- o Users can search the next five-day weather forecast for any city they desire.
- o Skills: HTML5, CSS, Bootstrap, Javascript, Moment.js, Server-Side APIs

Get Route

http://get-route-group-5.herokuapp.com/ | https://github.com/wseban/Get-Route

- o Online marketplace.
- o Skills: Handlebars, Bootstrap, Express, Express-Sessions, MySQL, Sequelize, JavaScript

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Protection Specialist, Gavin de Becker & Associates

Feb 2020 – July 2021

Responsible for the safety, security, and privacy of numerous at-risk public figures and their families-providing them close-protection at scheduled (and non-scheduled) public appearances, and estate security. Areas of emphasis include: staying calm during stressful situations, customer service, building relationships, traumatic medical care, communicating effectively and water rescue.

- Trained and mentored a team of 12 recruits during initial entry classes resulting in 100% of personnel receiving a job offer as well as the company offering me a guaranteed team leader position.
- Successfully conducted a 3-person detail, alone, with zero incidents and a stellar approval rating.
- Mentored 4 peers resulting in a 20% increase in physical readiness and a 100% pass of the company's physical fitness test.

Small Business Owner, 'Merican Nutrition

Jun 2017 - Jun 2020

Responsible for coordinating, contracting and financing the construction of a brand-new business while simultaneously rescuing an existing business into turning a profit. Areas of emphasis include: establishing, teaching and training staff on operational procedures, customer service, building relationships, communicating effectively and budget management.

- Assembled and trained an intelligent, passionate team of highly motivated individuals increasing revenue by 400% within 30 days of acquisition.
- Coordinated and negotiated with multiple contractors resulting in no delays with construction of new business and a net savings of over \$40,000.
- Utilized cost analysis and mitigation to lower overhead of both businesses and increase profit by 20%.

Logistics Coordinator, US Army (O-3/GS12)

Mar 2016 - Jun 2017

Responsible for the planning and coordination of multi-functional logistics for an organization with over 1,000 personnel. Areas of emphasis include: deployment in support of Operation Enduring Freedom, support planning, project management, and budget management.

- Created initial support plans for the installation of two forward operating bases in the Middle East, while simultaneously coordinating the improvement of two locations overseas, resulting in a 50% increase of regional rocket artillery capabilities.
- Introduced a theater maintenance standard operating procedure, increasing team communication across the Middle East, resulting in an increase of equipment readiness by 70% and a net savings of over \$50,000.
- Managed and supervised 80 government credit cards, civilian travel, with an estimated value of \$50,000 per month, with zero outstanding delinquencies.

Operations and Planning Officer, US Army (O-2/GS11)

Aug 2015 - Mar 2016

Responsible for the planning, coordination, and training for an organization of 400 personnel. Areas of emphasis included: land and ammunition management, training cycle management, and annual training planning and coordination.

- Planned, resourced, and executed four organizational events, training 300 personnel on their mission essential tasks, resulting in a 30% increase of the unit's deployable measurement.
- Established and implemented an 18-month training framework and de-conflicted multiple organizations' annual calendars, resulting in a 15% increase of all training across multiple levels.
- Created and applied weekly meetings to synchronize supported unit training schedules and resource requirements leading to a more efficient resource request system.

Operations Maintenance Supervisor, US Army (O-2/GS10)

Oct 2014 - Aug 2015

Responsible for asset readiness of over 500 pieces of equipment, valued in excess of \$80,000,000. Areas of emphasis included: establishing priorities, supervising the return of used stock items, and managing shop offices in acquiring, transporting, storing and issuing equipment parts.

- Developed and implemented alternative work schedules, within a week of assuming the position, resulting in a 98% decrease of late scheduled services.
- Established a waste reduction system of used vehicle parts, resulting in a savings of \$150,000.
- Implemented a weekly inspection with multiple section supervisors to ensure accurate deficiency reporting of their equipment; increased by 20%, resulting in an overall 90% equipment readiness.

Operations Supervisor, US Army (O-1/GS9)

Feb 2014 - Apr 2015

Responsible for the supervision of 83 Soldiers, accountable for all equipment and supplies in the organization. Areas of emphasis included: planning and coordinating training and overseeing the execution of essential tasks to improve the organization's deployable status.

- Planned and coordinated over 40 organized training events resulting in broadening all mechanic's knowledge on various pieces of equipment.
- Mentored soldiers accepted into officer candidate school, resulting in those Soldiers commissioning at the top of their officer candidate classes.